<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On Liberty and Power</title>
    <link>https://onliberty.press</link>
    <description>Political essays in the rhetorical tradition of 1750-1789 liberty writers, addressing contemporary events through an 18th-century philosophical lens.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://onliberty.press/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 12:00:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>On the Transfer of Men Into Torture</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=04</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=04</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:44:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>There are moments when a republic crosses a line so old and so clearly drawn that no elaborate theory is required to recognize it.  One need not argue policy outcomes, electoral mandates, or partisan...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Due Process in an Age of Urgency</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=03</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=03</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:39:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>I served in government long enough to understand how things work when authorities want something done quickly.  There are protocols.  There are reviews.  There are chains of command designed to ensure...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who will Stop You?  On Power, Pretense, and the State of the Republic</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=02</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=02</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:58:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>There are moments when the question before a Republic is no longer one of legality, but of recognition.  This is one of them.  A newly released recording, first reported by the Atlanta Journal-Constit...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Of Power Unbound by Law</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-23&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:13:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>When a government no longer feels itself bound by the law in the open light of day, the question before the people is no longer who among the accused is guilty, but whether the Republic yet endures....</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When a Republic Shields Those Who Prey Upon Its Children</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-21&amp;seq=02</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-21&amp;seq=02</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>When a government hides the truth about crimes against children, it ceases to be a guardian of justice and becomes instead a custodian of guilt.  We are told, yet again, to be patient.   We are told t...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the First Branch Abdicates</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-21&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-21&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:11:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>I spent years in government service.  Not in Congress, but near enough to watch how institutions work when they&apos;re healthy and how they fail when something fundamental shifts.  What former members are...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Republic That Rations Care</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-20&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-20&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>“Wherefore, security being the true design and end of government, it unanswerably follows that whatever form thereof appears most likely to ensure it to us, with the least expense and greatest benefit...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December 16, 1773 Was Not About Tea</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-16&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-16&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The Boston Tea Party is often reduced to a costume drama: men in disguise, crates in the harbor, a symbolic act of rebellion that looks tidy in hindsight.  But the men who boarded those ships were not...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Before the Shot Heard Round the World</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-14&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-14&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>A 250th Anniversary Reflection on Power, Law, and the Years 1763 to 1774  As the United States approaches the 250th anniversary of its founding, public memory naturally gravitates toward familiar mome...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winning Without Firing a Shot</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-13&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-13&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>We are losing, not because an enemy defeated us, but because they no longer need to.  I grew up as a military kid on Strategic Air Command bases in the 1980s. I’ve spent more than 30 years studying U....</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All People Are Created Equal</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-04&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-12-04&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>There are times in our history when fear or frustration tempts us to sort people into categories, “us” and “them.”  Times when whole groups become targets because of what they look like, where they co...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the Rules Break Down: Reflections on the Reported Killing of Survivors at Sea</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-29&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-29&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 18:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>A month ago, I wrote about why the rule of law is not optional in war.  Recent reporting that a U.S. strike may have intentionally killed survivors of a disabled boat as they clung to wreckage makes t...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Matter of Scouting</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-25&amp;seq=02</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-25&amp;seq=02</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>As a Scout overseas at Clark Air Base in the Philippines, Scouting was more than a hobby, it was stability, community, and a blueprint for what service should look like.  Those lessons carried me thro...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Foreign Policy Looks Like an Influence Operation</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-25&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-25&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>As someone who has spent years in national security and government service, the reporting that emerged this week should alarm every American, regardless of party.  Bloomberg and other outlets publishe...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Cost of DOGE</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-24&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-24&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>I’ve spent a career making government more efficient.  At the Department of Defense, I built a system called WatchTower that eliminated a four-year case backlog in eight months, not by firing people o...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commentary:  What Scouts Understood</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-22&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-22&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Shortly after the Russians invaded Ukraine, the scouts in my troop were deliberating how to spend the money they raised at a recent hot dog sale.  Some percentage to their summer camp account and some...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Constitution, the Military Oath, and the Limits of Presidential Power</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-20&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-20&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The recent claim that members of Congress committed “seditious behavior, punishable by death” for reminding service members to refuse unlawful orders deserves to be evaluated against the actual law, n...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Gettysburg Address Offers Us This Week</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-19&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-19&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Lincoln spoke only 272 words, but they were designed for moments exactly like this one - moments when the nation feels uneasy, institutions look compromised, and public trust strains under the weight...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Citizens in Uniform Start Asking Questions</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-16&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-16&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Recent reporting about the growing unease among National Guard members is not merely a story about troop deployments.  It’s a window into a deeper problem that anyone who has worn a uniform should rec...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the Truth Becomes Uncomfortable: A Test of Our Democratic Character</title>
      <link>https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-14&amp;seq=01</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onliberty.press/article.html?date=2025-11-14&amp;seq=01</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>In moments like this, when the release of long-demanded documents collides with political identity, we learn something important about the health of our democracy. Not about one party or another, but...</description>
      <author>Publius</author>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>